Bibliothèque nationale de France: Medieval Manuscript Photograph Collection
Yale University Arts Library
Bibliothèque nationale de France: Medieval Manuscript Photograph Collection
1979-
VRC 316
Yale University Arts Library
16.25
15 boxes
Gift of glass negatives and black and white unmounted photographs of medieval manuscripts in the Bibliotheque National, Paris. Rich, but not comprehensive, coverage. Assortment of full page illustrations and details, some duplicates. Known as the Tuefferd-Servant gift, acquired through Sumner McKnight Crosby.
Bibliothèque nationale de France
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Scope and Contents
Gift of glass negatives and black and white unmounted photographs of medieval manuscripts in the Bibliotheque National, Paris. Rich, but not comprehensive, coverage. Assortment of full page illustrations and details, some duplicates. Known as the Tuefferd-Servant gift, acquired through Sumner McKnight Crosby.
Arrangement
Photographs in individual folders divided by manuscript labeled with title and shelf number. Glass negatives in original boxes as organized by donor.
Illumination of books and manuscripts; Photographs; Reproductions
- Manuscript Covers for Bib. Nat. Lat. 9455(?) and Bib. Nat. Lat. 17326, plus handwritten inventory of entire gift with some discrepancies (4 photographs) (Box 1)
- Folder containing photographs of manuscripts requiring further identification (50 photographs) (Box 1)
- Bib. Nat. Ms. Lat. 1, Tours School, Vivian Bible of Charles the Bald, (22 photographs) (Box 1)
- Bib. Nat. Ms. Lat. 2, Franco-Saxon School, Second Bible of Charles the Bald (59 photographs) (Box 1)
- Bib. Nat. Ms. Lat. 5, Limoges School, First Bible of St. Martial, (27 photographs) (Box 1)
- Bib. Nat. Ms. Lat. 8, Limoges School, Second Bible of St. Martial, (28 photographs) (Box 1)
- Bib. Nat. Ms. Lat. 104, Bible, fragment, (3 photographs) (Box 1)
- Bib. Nat. Ms. Lat. 248, Paris School, Bible of Philip the Fair, (2 photographs) (Box 1)
- Bib. Nat. Ms. Lat. 257, Franco-Saxon School, Gospels of Francis I, (21 photographs) (Box 1)
- Bib. Nat. Ms. Lat. 266, Tours School, Lothair Gospels, (44 photographs) (Box 1)
- Bib. Nat. Ms. Lat. 776, Gradual, (3 photographs) (Box 1)
- Bib. Nat. Ms. Lat. 796, Breviary of Montieramey, (4 photographs) (Box 1)
- Bib. Nat. Ms. Lat. 871, Cologne School, Sacramentary of St, Gereon, (22 photographs) (Box 1)
- Bib. Nat. Ms. Lat. 833, Missal, (11 photographs) (Box 1)
- Bib. Nat. Ms. Lat. 920, Jean Colombe, Hours of Louis de Laval, (35 photographs) (Box 1)
- Bib. Nat. Ms. Lat. 946, Rhenish School, Pontifical, end of XIII c., (28 photographs) (Box 1)
- Bib. Nat. Ms. Lat. 819, Liege School, Sacramentary, (2 photographs) (Box 1)
- Bib. Nat. Ms. Lat. 919, Hesdin, Jacquemart de, Grandes Heures of Jean de Berry, (1 photograph) (Box 1)
- Bib. Nat. Ms. Lat. 1141, Corbie School, Sacramentary, (10 photographs) (Box 1)
- Bib. Nat. Ms. Lat. 1156A, Workshop of Rohan Master, Hours of Rene d'Anjou, (2 photographs) (Box 1)
- Bib. Nat. Ms. Lat. 1156B, Hours of Marguerite d'Orleans, (7 photographs) (Box 1)
- Bib. Nat. Ms. Lat. 1369, Workshop of Rohan Master, hours of Isabella Stuart, duchess of Brittany, (3 photographs) (Box 1)
- Bib. Nat. Ms. Lat. 1171, Bourdichon, Jean (school of), Hours of Henri IV, (18 photographs) (Box 1)
- Bib. Nat. Ms. Lat. 1173, Hours of Charles d'Angouleme, (25 photographs) (Box 2)
- Bib. Nat. Ms. Lat. 1370, Rouen School, Hours of Charles VIII, (16 photographs) (Box 2)
- Bib. Nat. Ms. Lat. 1429, Hours of Henri II, (20 photographs) (Box 2)
- Bib. Nat. Ms. Lat. 1699, St. amand School, St. Hilaire de Poitiers, (1 photograph) (Box 2)
- Bib. Nat. Ms. Lat. 2287, North French School, St. Gregory, Letters, (2 photographs) (Box 2)
- Bib. Nat. Ms. Lat. 2293, (School of Figeac, Sacramentary of St. Saveur de Figeac, (1 photograph) (Box 2)
- Bib. Nat. Ms. Lat. 3779, School of Cluny, Lives of Saints with Homilies, (3 photographs) (Box 2)
- Bib. Nat. Ms. Lat. 3893, Paris School, Gratian, Decretals, (3 photographs) (Box 2)
- Bib. Nat. Ms. Lat. 5047, Northeast French School, Josephus, Jewish Antiquities (15 photographs) (Box 2)
- Bib. Nat. Ms. Lat. 5764, Caesar, Gallic Wars, (2 photographs) (Box 2)
- Bib. Nat. Ms. Lat. 6067, Conquest of Constantinople?, (35 photographs) (Box 2)
- Bib. Nat. Ms. Lat. 6643, Unidentified manuscript, early 16th c., (7 photographs) (Box 2)
- Bib. Nat. Ms. Lat. 8823, Bible, end of 12 c., (2 photographs) (Box 2)
- Bib. Nat. Ms. Lat. 8846, Canterbury School, Copy of Utrecht Psalter, (62 photographs) (Box 2)
- Bib. Nat. Ms. Lat. 8850, Rhine School, Gospels of St. Medard de Soissons, (10 photographs) (Box 2)
- Bib. Nat. Ms. Lat. 8865, Paris School, Lambert of St. Omer, Liber Floridus, (6 photographs) (Box 2)
- Bib. Nat. Ms. Lat. 8878, St. Sever, Beatus of Libiena, Commentary on the Apocalypse, (88 photographs) (Box 2)
- Bib. Nat. Ms. Lat. 8886, Missal and Pontifical of Etienne Loypeau, Bishop of Lucon, 1407, (9 photographs) (Box 2)
- Bib. Nat. Ms. Lat. 8959, Northeast French School, Josephus, Jewish Antiquities, (14 photographs) (Box 2)
- Bib. Nat. Ms. Lat. 9395, East French School, Gospel Book (14 photographs) (Box 2)
- Bib. Nat. Ms. Lat. 9396, School of Latin Kingdom, Jerusalem, Gospel of St. John, c. 1130-1140, (2 photographs) (Box 2)
- Bib. Nat. Ms. Lat. 9436, Paris School, Missal of St. Denis, mid-XI c., (16 photographs) (Box 2)
- Bib. Nat. Ms. Lat. 9437, Savoy School Hours of Louis of Savoy, 1440-1465, (18 photographs) (Box 2)
- Bib. Nat. Ms. Lat. 9438, Limoges School, Sacramentary of the Cathedral of St. Etienne, c. 1100, (28 photographs) (Box 2)
- Bib. Nat. Ms. Lat. 9474, Bourdichon, Jean, Grandes Heures of Anne of Brittany, (103 photographs) (Box 2)
- Bib. Nat. Ms. Lat. 10421, Bible, 13th c., (15 photographs) (Box 3)
- Bib. Nat. Ms. Lat. 10426, Paris School Bible, c. 1270, (2 photographs) (Box 3)
- Bib. Nat. Ms. Lat. 10465, Unidentified manuscript, (2 photographs) (Box 3)
- Bib. Nat. Ms. Lat. 10474, Apocalypse, late 13th c., (10 photographs) (Box 3)
- Bib. Nat. Ms. Lat. 10491, Georges Trubert, Breviary of Rene II of Lorraine, (9 photographs) (Box 3)
- Bib. Nat. Ms. Lat. 10514, Trier School, Poussay Gospel Lectionary, (36 photographs) (Box 3)
- Bib. Nat. Ms. Lat. 10528, Paris School, Hours of Marguerite de Clisson, (5 photographs) (Box 3)
- Bib. Nat. Ms. Lat. 10559, Rouen School, Book of Hours, beg. 16th c., (1 photograph) (Box 3)
- Bib. Nat. Ms. Lat. 10567, Frederic Brentel, Hours of Guillaume de Bade, 1647, (31 photographs) (Box 3)
- Bib. Nat. Ms. Lat. 11506-11510, Grenoble School (?), Bible, late 12th c., (100 photographs) (Box 3)
- Bib. Nat. Ms. Lat. 11512, Fragment of a Bible, (2 photographs) (Box 3)
- Bib. Nat. Ms. Lat. 11534-11535, North French School, Partial copy of a Manerius Bible, S. Genevieve, 8-10, end of 12th c., (32 photographs) (Box 3)
- Bib. Nat. Ms. Lat. 11548, Northeast French School, Bible, mid-12th c., ((9 photographs) (Box 3)
- Bib. Nat. Ms. Lat. 11550, Paris School, Psalter-Hymnal, mid-11 c., (6 photographs) (Box 3)
- (7 photographs) (Box 3)
- Bib. Nat. Ms. Lat. 11565-11566, Paris School, Abbey of St.-Germain-des-Pres, Commentary on Psalms, late 12th c., (3 photographs) (Box 3)
- Bib. Nat. Ms. Lat. 11575-11576, Corbie School, St. Augustine, Expositio in epistolis pauli, 1164, (9 photographs) (Box 3)
- (4 photographs) (Box 3)
- Bib. Nat. Ms. Lat. 12056, School of Latin Kingdom of Jerusalem, Missal of the Holy Sepulchre of Jerusalem, second half of 12th c., (33 photographs) (Box 3)
- Bib. Nat. Ms. Lat. 12059, Cologne School, Missal, 1133, (4 photographs) (Box 3)
- Bib. Nat. Ms. Lat. 12117, Paris School, Abbey of St.-Germain-des-Pres, Collection of historical and cosmopgraphical works, mid-11th c., (24 photographs) (Box 3)
- (3 photographs) (Box 3)
- Bib. Nat. Ms. Lat. 15176, Cluny School, Bible of Odilo, (28 photographs) (Box 3)
- Bib. Nat. Ms. Lat. 16730, Corbie School, Josephus, Jewish Antiquities, (6 photographs) (Box 3)
- Bib. Nat. Ms. Lat. 16743-16744, School of the Abbey of St. Bertin, Bible of the Abbey of St. Bertin, late 12th or early 13th c., (1 photograph) (Box 3)
- Bib. Nat. Ms. Lat. 16827, Missal of Jean de Foix, Bishop of Comminges, 1492, (13 photographs) (Box 3)
- Bib. Nat. Ms. Lat. 17294, Bedford Master, workshop, Breviary of the Duke of Bedford, 1424-1435, (49 photographs) (Box 3)
- Bib. Nat. Ms. Lat. 17318, Paris School, Missal for St. Corneille at Compiegne, early 14th c., (3 photographs) (Box 4)
- Bib. Nat. Ms. Lat. 17325, Rhenish or Westphalian School, Lectionary, c. 1160, (3 photographs) (Box 4)
- Bib. Nat. Ms. Lat. 17326, Paris School, Gospels of the Sainte-Chapelle, c. 1260-1270, (13 photographs) (Box 4)
- Bib. Nat. Ms. Lat. 17961, Lower Rhenish School, Psalter of Frere Berthold, (4 photographs) (Box 4)
- (15 photographs) (Box 4)
- Bib. Nat. Ms. Lat. 17968, Reims School, Loisel Gospels, 845-882, (8 photographs) (Box 4)
- Bib. Nat. Ms. Lat. 18005, Reichenau School, Sacramentary, c. 1025, (4 photographs) (Box 4)
- Bib. Nat. Ms. Lat. 18014, Hesdin, Jacquemart de, and others, Petites Heures of Jean de Berry, (26 photographs) (Box 4)
- Bib. Nat. Ms. nouv. acq. Lat. 1390, School of Angers, Life of St. Aubin, end of 11th c., (14 photographs) (Box 4)
- Bib. Nat. Ms. nouv. acq. Lat. 1359, Paris School, History of the Foundation of the Monastery of St. Martin des Champs, mid-13th c., (4 photographs) (Box 4)
- (35 photographs) (Box 4)
- Bib. Nat. Ms. nouv. acq. Lat. 1416, Fouquet, Jean, Leaf from a Book of Hours for Etienne Chevalier, (2 photographs) (Box 4)
- Bib. Nat. Ms. nouv. acq. Lat. 1541, Evangeliary of St. Maximin de Treves, late 10th or early 11th c., (2 photographs) (Box 4)
- Bib. Nat. Ms. nouv. acq. Lat. 2196, Echternach School, Luxeuil Gospels, (31 photographs) (Box 4)
- Bib. Nat. Ms. nouv. acq. Lat. 2246, Cluny School, Lectionary, end of 11th c., (4 photographs) (Box 4)
- Bib. Nat. Ms. nouv. acq. Lat. 2290, Beatus, Commentary on the Apocalypse, early 13th c., (60 photographs) (Box 4)
- Bib. Nat. Ms. nouv. acq. Lat. 3024, Book of Hours, late 15th c., (1 photograph) (Box 4)
- (26 photographs) (Box 4)
- Bib. Nat. Ms. fr. 18, Maitre François, St. Augustine, La Cite de Dieu, (13 photographs) (Box 4)
- Bib. Nat. Ms. fr. 50, Maitre François, Vincent of Beauvais, Le Miroir historial, (15 photographs) (Box 4)
- Bib. Nat. Ms. fr. 126, Gille de Romme, Livre du Regime des Prines, (4 photographs) (Box 4)
- Bib. Nat. Ms. fr. 143, Painter of Charlese of Angouleme, Les Echecs amoureaux, c. 1500, (10 photographs) (Box 4)
- Bib. Nat. Ms. fr. 146, Paris School, Roman de Fauvel, early 14th c., (5 photographs) (Box 4)
- Bib. Nat. Ms. fr. 156-157, Paris School, Guyart des Moulins, Bible historiale, (5 photographs) (Box 4)
- Bib. Nat. Ms. fr. 159, Paris School, Guyart des Moulins, Bible historiale, (16 photographs) (Box 4)
- Bib. Nat. Ms. fr. 163, Paris School, Guyart des Moulins, Bible historiale, (1 photograph) (Box 4)
- Bib. Nat. Ms. fr. 166, Historiated bible, c. 1410, (24 photographs) (Box 4)
- Bib. Nat. Ms. fr. 167, Historiated bible, c. 1390, (5 photographs) (Box 4)
- Bib. Nat. Ms. fr. 170, St. Augustine, La Cite de Dieu, (3 photographs) (Box 4)
- Bib. Nat. Ms. fr. 226, Paris School, Boccaccio, Des Cas des nobles homes et femmes, c. 1415, (4 photographs) (Box 4)
- Bib. Nat. Ms. fr. 242, Jacobus de Voragine, Legend d'Oree, (2 photographs) (Box 4)
- Bib. Nat. Ms. fr. 247, Jean Fouquet and others, Josephus, Les Antiquities judaiques, begun, c. 1410, (11 photographs) (Box 4)
- Bib. Nat. Ms. fr. 259, Workshop of Boucicaut Master, Livy, Histoire romaine, (7 photographs) (Box 4)
- Bib. Nat. Ms. fr. 263, Livy, Histoire romaine, (3 photographs) (Box 5)
- Bib. Nat. Ms. fr. 289, Bruges School (?), Valerius Maximus, Faits et dits memorables, c. 1470, (6 photographs) (Box 5)
- Bib. Nat. Ms. fr. 380, Jean de Meung and Guillaume de Lorris, Le roman de la Rose, (4 photographs) (Box 5)
- Bib. Nat. Ms. fr. 403, Apocalypse, second half of 13th century, (7 photographs) (Box 5)
- Bib. Nat. Ms. fr. 574, Cossouin de Metz, L'Image du Monde, (3 photographs) (Box 5)
- Bib. Nat. Ms. fr. 594, Rouen School, Petrarch, Triumphs, 1503, (7 photographs) (Box 5)
- Bib. Nat. Ms. fr. 598, Paris School, Boccaccio, Des Cas des nobles homes et femmes, c. 1403, (6 photographs) (Box 5)
- Bib. Nat. Ms. fr. 606, Paris School, Christine de Pisan, L'Epître d'Othea a Hector, c. 1400-1402, (7 photographs) (Box 5)
- Bib. Nat. Ms. fr. 810, Honore Bonet, L'Apparacion de Jean de Meung, (1 photograph) (Box 5)
- Bib. Nat. Ms. fr. 823, Guillaume de Sigulleville, Le Pelerinage de vie humain, 1393, (7 photographs) (Box 5)
- Bib. Nat. Ms. fr. 836, Paris School, Christine de Pisan, Oeuvres, c. 1405, (5 photographs) (Box 5)
- Bib. Nat. Ms. fr. 844, Collection of Songs, (2 photographs) (Box 5)
- Bib. Nat. Ms. fr. 858, Breviary of Love of Master Ermengau, (6 photographs) (Box 5)
- Bib. Nat. Ms. fr. 861, Virgil, Aeneid, c. 1500, (8 photographs) (Box 5)
- Bib. Nat. Ms. fr. 938, western French School (?), Fr. Laurent, La Somme le roi, 1294, (16 photographs) (Box 5)
- Bib. Nat. Ms. fr. 966, Passion of Christ and Lamentations of St. Bernard, (1 photograph) (Box 5)
- Bib. Nat. Ms. fr. 1082, Nicholas Oresme, Aristotle's of the Earth and Sky, late 14th c., (1 photograph) (Box 5)
- Bib. Nat. Ms. fr. 1174, Montferrant, Les douze dames de rhetorique, late 15th c., (4 photographs) (Box 5)
- Bib. Nat. Ms. fr. 1433, Paris School, Le roman de l'atre perilleux, c. 1330, (6 photographs) (Box 5)
- Bib. Nat. Ms. fr. 1460, The Song of Garan de Monglenne, (2 photographs) (Box 5)
- Bib. Nat. Ms. fr. 1463, Rustician de Pise, Le Roman de Meliadus, (4 photographs) (Box 5)
- Bib. Nat. Ms. fr. 1989, Michault, La Dance aux aveugles and Rene d'anjou, L'Abuse en cour, (4 photographs) (Box 5)
- Bib. Nat. Ms. fr. 2364, Romance of Alexander (?), (10 photographs) (Box 5)
- Bib. Nat. Ms. fr. 2623, Chroniques de Normandie, (5 photographs) (Box 5)
- Bib. Nat. Ms. fr. 2645, Bruges School, Jean Froissart, Chronicles, (7 photographs) (Box 5)
- Bib. Nat. Ms. fr. 2685, Jean de Courcy, Chronicles, (3 photographs) (Box 5)
- Bib. Nat. Ms. fr. 2689, George Chastelain, fragment of the Chronicles of the Dukes of Burgundy (1 photograph) (Box 5)
- Bib. Nat. Ms. fr. 2692, Rene d'Anjou, Traite de la forme et devis comme on fait les tournois (7 photographs) (Box 5)
- Bib. Nat. Ms. fr. 2695, Master of Rene d'Anjou, Livre des tournois, c. 1460-65, (5 details) (Box 5)
- Bib. Nat. Ms. fr. 2810, Boucicaut Master and Bedford Master, Le Livre des merveilles, c. 1410, (9 photographs) (Box 5)
- (2 photographs) (Box 5)
- Bib. Nat. Ms. fr. 6465, Jean Fouquet, Les Grandes Chroniques de France, c. 1458, (13 photographs) (Box 5)
- (26 photographs) (Box 5)
- Bib. Nat. Ms. fr. 9220, School of Picardy, Le Verger de Soulas, (4 photographs) (Box 5)
- Bib. Nat. Ms. fr. 9749, Paris School Valerius Maximus, Faits et dits memorables, c. 1375, (5 photographs) (Box 6)
- Bib. Nat. Ms. fr. 12420, Paris School, Boccaccio, Des claires et nobles femmes, c. 1402, (16 photographs) (Box 6)
- Bib. Nat. Ms. fr. 12584, Renard the Fox, (9 photographs) (Box 6)
- Bib. Nat. Ms. fr. 13096, Apocalypse, (12 photographs) (Box 6)
- Bib. Nat. Ms. fr. 13429, Albert Pigghe, Commentaires della guerre gallique, vol. II, (30 photographs) (Box 6)
- Bib. Nat. Ms. fr. 13568, Paris School, Joinville, Vie de St. Louis, c. 1360, (2 photographs) (Box 6)
- Bib. Nat. Ms. fr. 19039, Guillaume de Tignonville, Dits des philosophes and Rene d'Anjou, Mortifiement de vaine plaisance, (6 photographs) (Box 6)
- Bib. Nat. Ms. fr. 19819, Jean Fouquet, Statutes of the Order of St. Michael, 1470, (1 photograph) (Box 6)
- Bib. Nat. Ms. fr. 32531, Workshops of the Rohan Master and Bedford Master, Barthelemy l'Anglais, Livre de la propriete des choses, c. 1410-1415, (12 photographs) (Box 6)
- Bib. Nat. Ms. fr. 22532, Barthelemy l'Anglais, Livre de la propriete des choses, (15 photographs) (Box 6)
- Bib. Nat. Ms. fr. 23279, Workshop of the Boucicaut Master, Pierre Salmon, Reponses a Charles VI at Lamentation au roi sur son etat, (12 photographs) (Box 6)
- (7 photographs) (Box 6)
- Bib. Nat. Ms. fr. 24461, Sketchbook, designs for tapestries and stained glass, (14 photographs) (Box 6)
- Bib. Nat. Ms. fr. 25528, Boccaccio, Il Filostrato, (3 photographs) (Box 6)
- (25 photographs) (Box 6)
- Bib. Nat. Ms. all. 34, Cologne School, Meditations on the Life of St. Catherine(?), (10 photographs) (Box 6)
- Bib. Nat. Ms. all. 106, Unidentified manuscript, (1 photograph) (Box 6)
- Bib. Nat. Ms. all. 113, Alchemical text, (7 photographs) (Box 6)
- Bib. Nat. Ms. all. 222, Rhenish School, (4 photographs) (Box 6)
- Bib. Nat. Ms. Ital. 115, Pseudo-Bonaventura, Meditations on the Life of Christ, (9 photographs) (Box 6)
- Bib. Ars. Ms. 610, Sacramentary of Worms, (12 photographs) (Box 6)
- Bib. Ars. Ms. 638, Ghent-Bruges School, Book of Hours, (24 photographs) (Box 6)
- (14 photographs) (Box 6)
- (9 photographs) (Box 6)
- Laon, Bib. Mun. MS. 550, School of Alsace(?), Evangeliary, end of XII c., (8 photographs) (Box 6)
- Glass Negatives: Many negative numbers are available in printed format in boxes 1-6 of this collection
- Glass negatives: Mss. Lat. 1, 2, 2196, 2290, 3024, 3027, 9474; Fr. 166, 22531, 22532, 23279, 24364, plus one box of unidentified negatives (Box 7)
- Glass negatives: Mss. Lat. 819, 833, 873, 919, 1177, 1178, 1188, 1394, 1403, 1407, 1408, 1416, 11506, 11507, 11509, 11510, 11008, 12055, 12056, 12117, 12302, 17961, 17968, 18005, 18014, 18017 (Box 8)
- Glass negatives: Mss. Lat. 104, 163, 248, 257, 924, 946, 1141, 1156, 1173, 1179, 1284, 1328, 1369, 1370, 1390, 1393, 8878, 10421, 10528, 10529, 10540, 10553, 10559, 11512, 11534, 11535, 11548, 11550, 11564, 11565, 11566, 11576, 11580 (Box 9)
- Glass negatives: Mss. Lat. 266, 441, 756, 796, 1428, 1429, 1654, 1699, 2196, 2287, 2293, 2692, 3893, 5047, 5764, 6643, 6067, 3779, 8886, 8959, 9395, 9396, 9436, 9438, 12420, 13263, 13273, 17318, 17329, 17116, 17325 (Box 10)
- Glass negatives: Mss. Lat. 183, 215, 920, 1181, 1359, 1366, 1390, 1416, 1404, 1541, 1721, 2246, 6445, 8823, 8846, 8850, 8865, 12706, 13293, 13294, 13297, 13305, 15176, 16730, 16743, 16827, 17294 (Box 11)
- Glass negatives: Ms. Lat. 10567, 18024, 18026, 43193; Ms. Fr. 606, 616, 609, 810, 823, 836, 844, 858, 861, 938, 966, 1082, 1174, 1433, 1460, 1463, 4274, 5594, 5716, 6440, 6494, 9749, 12538, 12584, 13429, 13096, 13568, 19039, 19819, 24461, 25528 (Box 12)
- Glass negatives: Ms. Lat. 18, 50, 91, 126, 143, 146, 157, 159, 163, 166, 167, 170, 174, 191, 216, 226, 242, 247, 259, 263, 289, 380, 403, 574, 594, 598, 1989, 2364, 2623, 2649, 2685, 2689, 2692, 2870, 6455, 9198, 9199; Ms. Lat.? 9455, 17366 (Box 13)
- Glass negatives: 3 boxes of negatives without identifying shelf numbers; Ms. Italien 115; Laon, Bib. Mun. MS. 550; Ms. all. 34, 106, 113, 222; Bib. Ars. Ms. 417, 638, 5064; Bib. Ste.-Genevieve, Ms. 1190 (Box 14)
- Large format glass negatives: Ms. Lat. 1, 52, 873, 1366, 4889, 8846, 8859, 8878, 9392, 9395, 11939, 11948, 11964, 11973, 11980, 17325; Ms. fr. 166, 616, 2695 (Box 15)